你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
在上一个视频中，您了解了终端和shell之间的区别，并且还了解了
In the last video you learn the difference between the terminal and the shell and you've also seen how
命令的结构相当笼统。
commands are structured on quite a general level.
我们提到了命令遵循一般结构，如命令名Vincent选项，然后
We mentioned that commands follow a general structure like command name Vincent options and then some
输入。
inputs.
但是，正如我们所看到的，每个Linux命令的实现略有不同，它们的行为也略有不同
But like we saw each of the Linux commands is implemented slightly differently and they behave slightly
不一样的。
differently.
那么，除了记住无数不同的实现方式之外，我们如何才能真正知道
So other than memorizing a jillion different implementations of things how can we actually know how
正确使用每个Linux命令。
to use each of the Linux commands properly.
答案当然是使用手册页，也就是手册页。
Well the answer is to use the manual pages known as man pages for sure.
现在，Linux附带了一组令人难以置信的手册页面，这些页面将详细介绍
Now Linux comes with an incredible set of manual pages that will detail the workings of pretty much
系统上的所有东西，包括命令。
everything on the system including commands.
因此，在这段视频中，我们将介绍手册是如何构建的，因为手册非常庞大。
So in this video we're going to be covering how the manual is structured now because the manual is massive.
了解它背后的结构将使它更容易导航，因为
Having an understanding of the structure behind it is going to make it so much easier to navigate because
这样你就不仅知道手册里有什么，而且还知道到哪里去找。
then you'll know not only what is available in the manual but also where to look for it.
因此，在视频结束时，您将了解手册结构以及哪些部分
So by the end of the video you'll have an understanding of the manual structure and which sections are
可能对你来说最重要的是，你还会有一张很酷的小抄可以带走
probably going to be most important to you and you'll also have a cool cheat sheet to take away with
你几乎拥有这段视频中所有的笔记和所有的热门信息。
you that pretty much has all the notes and all the all the top information from this video.
那是相当令人兴奋的。
That's quite exciting.
因此，让我们继续并直接投入其中。
So let's go ahead and jump right into it.
好的，当您查看手动结构时，您需要知道的第一件事是
All right so the first thing you need to know when you're looking at the manual structure is that the
手册分为八个部分，每个部分都涉及一种特定类型的东西
manual is broken up into eight sections and each of these sections deals with a specific type of thing
它位于您的Linux操作系统上。
that is on your Linux operating system.
现在的手册绝对是庞大的，如果一切都只是简单的，那是不可能处理的
Now the manual is absolutely huge and be just it would be impossible to deal with if it was all just
在一个大肿块里。
in one big lump.
但是把它分成几个部分会让你和我更容易处理
But breaking it up into several sections that makes it a lot easier for you and I to manage and some
我们要找的地方。
where we're looking.
这样我们才能真正找到我们要找的东西。
So we can actually find what we're looking for.
好的。
OK.
那么，让我们逐一浏览这八个部分，并对以下内容有更多的了解
So let's go through each of these eight sections and have a bit of a bit more understanding of what
他们是这样做的。
they do.
好的。
OK.
那么让我们从第一节开始吧。
So let's start with section number one.
因此，第一部分是针对用户命令的。
So section number one is for user commands.
现在，任何普通用户都可以从shell运行这些命令。
Now these are commands that can just be run from the shell by any regular user.
您不需要任何特定的管理权限或任何root权限即可运行这些
You don't need any particular administration privileges or any root privileges to be able to run these
命令。
commands.
任何人都可以将它们用于日期命令、命令等等。
Anyone can use them for things like the date command the command and so on.
这些命令属于用户命令，并且几乎属于您将使用的任何命令
These are the kind of command that would come under user commands and pretty much any command that you'll
使用日期将在那里。
use day to will be in there.
好的。
OK.
第2节针对的是系统调用。
Section 2 is for system calls.
现在这是一个更高级的部分。
Now this is a more advanced section.
这就是包含可在您编写的应用程序中使用的编程函数
So this is this contains programming functions that can be used within an application that you write
为了调用Linux内核，它是操作系统的一个非常低级的部分，我们将
to make calls to the Linux kernel which is a very low level part of the operating system that we'll
我们稍后会在课程中讨论。
be discussing actually later on in the course.
但除非你在做一些相当高级的东西，可以真正与操作系统配合使用，而且
But unless you're doing some rather advanced stuff that actually plays with the operating system and
你计算机上的硬件，你可能不会使用第二部分，但它就在那里，这就是它的用途。
the hardware on your computer you probably won't use Section 2 but it's there and that's what it's for.
第3节也是如此，它是关于C库函数的。
Same kind of goes for Section 3 which is about C library functions.
现在，这些是C编程语言的库。
Now these are libraries for the C programming language.
这些函数和库为您的计算机上的特定事物提供接口，例如
And these are functions and libraries that provide interfaces to specific things on your computer such
作为图形用户界面或其他库，如果您正在编写一些C++语言，您可能会想要使用这些库
as graphical user interfaces or other libraries that you might want to use if you're writing some C
你想用来访问你的计算机的代码，那就是你要做的事情
code that you want to have access to your computer with then that's the kind of stuff that you will
请看第3节中的，但是如果您像我一样只是一个普通用户，那么您可能不需要
be looking at in the in section 3 but if you're just a regular user like me you probably won't need
才能做到这一点。
to do so.
第四节是设备和特殊文件，里面总是有“特殊”这个词。
Section 4 is devices and special files always got the word special in it.
但这是关于如何管理您计算机上的不同设备。
But this is about how the different device is on your computer are managed.
比如CD驱动器或者随机数生成器或者美国端口之类的东西
So things such as CD drives or things such as random number generators or things such as U.S. ports
诸如此类的事情。
and stuff like that.
这就是它们的管理方式，以及如何使用命令行等方式访问它们。
This is how they're managed and how you can access those using using command lines and things like that.
因此，任何与设备有关的内容都不会出现在第4节中。
So anything to do with the device isn't going to be in Section 4.
第5节是一个有趣的部分，第5节是关于文件格式和约定的，所以如果您曾经打开过
Section 5 is an interesting one Section 5 is about file formats and conventions so if you've ever opened
在你的电脑上上传了一个文件，然后就像是哇，那是什么。
up a file on your computer and just been like whoa what is that.
看起来绝对是一团糟。
Looks like an absolute mess.
我不知道怎么回事，我怎么可能用这个。
I have no idea what is going on how can I possibly use this.
这就是第5节的内容。第5节介绍了所有不同的格式和特定格式的约定
That's what Section 5 is for Section 5 is about all the different formats and the conventions of specific
文件和您的计算机上。
files and on your computer.
因此您知道Word文档格式或PDA记录特定配置格式的格式
So you know formats for word documents or formats where PDA documents a format for specific configuration
文件，如果您想要开始在您的计算机上配置内容，以便自定义内容。
files if you want to start configuring things on your computer so customizing stuff.
第5节是您将经常使用的部分，因为它将向您展示每个特殊文件是如何工作的
Section 5 is what you're going to use often because it'll show you how each of the special files works
以及它们是如何构造的，以及您可以更改它们的数据结构。
and how they're structured and which you data structure you can change them.
正确的。
Right.
所以第5节第6节是关于游戏的。
So that Section 5 section 6 is about games.
安装在您的计算机上的任何游戏都有自己的分区和不同的命令
Any games that are installed on your computer they have their own section and different commands and
因此，可以复制到第7节的是更多的杂物，更多的未分类的东西。
so replicable to those sections 7 is more miscellaneous stuff more Uncategorized stuff.
所以它通常是协议或文件系统之类的东西，以及有关它们的信息。
So it's usually stuff like protocols or file systems and information about those.
如果你知道它们是什么意思，那么也许你想去看看。
If you know what they mean then maybe you want to check it out.
如果你不这样做，那就别担心，你可能永远也不会遇到它。
If you don't then don't worry about it you'll probably never come across it.
第8节删除了所有与系统管理有关的内容。
And Section 8 is lilted of all the stuff to do with system administration.
这就像是第1节的反面第8节是实际上可以执行的所有命令
So this is like the reverse of section 1 Section 8 is all the commands that can actually that actually
需要root权限和管理权限才能在您的计算机上运行，如下所示
require root privileges and administration privileges to be run on your computers this is things like
更改密码。
changing passwords.
这就像你知道的，在你的计算机上真正编辑重要的东西，设置自动化和
This is things like you know really editing important stuff on your computer setting up automation and
诸如此类的事情。
things like that.
而第1节用户命令是任何人都可以运行的东西。
Whereas Section 1 the user commands is stuff that anyone can run.
第8节需要特权才能实际运行这些命令的那些功能。
Section 8 requires privileges in order to actually run those functions of those commands.
好的。
OK.
这就是八个部分。
So those are the eight sections.
正如我所说的，这个有更多解释的信息实际上在您可以获得的小抄中
And as I say this information with more explanation is actually in the cheat sheet that you can get
在参考资料部分，所以一定要在此视频之后查看。
in the resources section so make sure to check that out after this video.
但是您实际要使用的主要部分是第1节，即用户命令
But the main sections that you're actually going to be using Section 1 which is the user commands will
在本课程中一直在使用它，并且您几乎在任何时候都会一直使用它
be using that all the time in this course and you will be using it all the time pretty much whenever
您今天使用的是Linux Day。
you use Linux day today.
如果您想要开始编辑和配置内容，通常需要使用第5节。
Section 5 is usually what you use if you want to start editing stuff and configuring things.
您将获得有关如何编辑这些内容以及如何使用在特定配置文件中编辑哪些内容的信息
You'll get information on how to edit the stuff and what to edit in specific configuration files using
第5节和第8节当您想要设置像自动化这样的东西或使一些相当高级的东西
Section 5 and section 8 when you want to set up things like automation or make some rather advanced
更改您的计算机，然后您将使用第8节，它是所有系统管理内容，
changes to your computer then you'll use Section 8 which is all the System Administration stuff that's
当您想要做普通用户不应该一直做的事情时。
when you want to do stuff that normal users shouldn't be able to do all the time.
这就像更改、修补其他人的密码，以及为系统创建用户之类的事情
It's like changing patching other people's passwords and stuff like that creating users for the system
诸如此类的事情。
and things like that.
好的。
OK.
因此，第1节、第5节和第8节可能是您最常使用的。
So Section 1 Section 5 and section 8 are what you will likely use most often.
这就是我们所看到的，这是手册的一个结构，对我们所看到的内容做了一个快速的总结
So there we are that's a that's a structure for the manual does take a quick summary of what we've seen
在这里，我们已经看到MAN Linux菜单被分成八个部分，以及关于每个部分的更多信息
here we've seen the man Linux menus broken up into eight sections and more information about each of
这些部分实际上位于您可以在参考资料中找到的小抄中。
the sections is actually in the cheat sheet that you can find in the resources.
但是现在我们已经理解了每一节，并且我们了解了手册的结构
But now that we've got an understanding of each of the sections and we see how the manual is structured
让我们开始实际使用它吧。
Let's start actually using it.
好的。
OK.
所以在下一个视频中，我们要做的是将这些信息
So in the next video what we're going to do is we're going to take this information about the those
结构，我们将了解如何实际搜索手册并阅读手册页面
structures and we're going to see how you can actually search the manual and read the manual pages to
了解如何使用新命令。
learn how to use new commands.
好了，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that goodness I'll see you in the next video.